Ch02 - I’ll die if I work…!

“Menu! Wait!? Stop! Cancel! Undo!”

Opening a semitransparent window in the air, the blonde-haired loli… Rokuko, yelled at it, but it didn’t look like there was any reaction at all. Yeah, her yapping’s getting noisy already. This is why kids are…

“Oi, quiet down a bit, you’re being noisy. Rather, shut up.”
“W-what, you can’t order—… –…”

Silence.
Ah, right, I’m the Master huh. And what the Master says is absolute. Fufufu.
I didn’t plot for it, but perhaps the refined life of [Not Working] made its way to me?
Right, I don’t particularly have to work. Leaving it all to this blonde loli, I’ll spend my life sleeping leisurely!
… … .. Yep. I was just thinking about it, but that’s super trashy.

“… Still though, she’s a young girl. Thinking about it normally…”

I’d probably be able to fully enjoy sleeping all the time and live in luxury like a gigolo if she were at least the same age as me or a senior… but I can’t even say if her age has two digits or not.

“Uhhh, menu? Oh, it seriously popped up. Lets see, there’s this and that…”

A semitransparent window came out in response to my words… yep, that’s a menu window alright. It’s ordered in a way that’s easy to understand. It was divided into three major categories.

Labyrinth
Subordinates
DP

It was in polite Japanese (and English)… well, maybe I was just able to read the words like that thanks to God? That’s probably it.

“… —! … —!”

Oh, Rokuko is glaring at me with a pretty amazing glare. Hahah, little girls aren’t scary even if they glare, it’s just too cute! Let’s pat her head. Ah, now she’s more angry. She’s shouting in silence.

“If you want to say something, say it.”
“Trash! Stupid! —Ah, m-my voice finally worked, idiot! What did you do!”
“Yeah, the idiot’s you, Rokuko. Somehow or another, I’m your master. In other words, it looks like I ended up becoming the Dungeon Master.”
“Cancel it!”
“Why?”
“I-I-I’m the greatest! So—! Obey me!”

The blonde little girl looked at me in anger and tears. Her face is going red… this is a problem.
I understand, this girl’s an idiot.

“Who’s an idiot!”
“Oops, did I say that out loud? But think about it… why did you summon me?”
“Well, to make you a dungeon monster!”
“In other words, if I obey you, I’ll have to fight as a dungeon monster and die if I fail. I’d probably die even if I didn’t fail. I mean, I like sleeping, but I’d like to avoid taking the journey into the eternal sleep.”
“W-well that’s just how it is for dungeon monsters… besides, you’re weak…”
“You can call me Keima.”
“Nn, understood, Kehma… gu—, I can’t disobey…!”
“Let’s try looking over the dungeon for now. Beds are best when they’re safe after all.”

I chose [Labyrinth] from the menu. I was operating it like a touch panel, but it looks like it works with voice recognition too.
Well, with the state of the dungeon displayed in front of me, I froze.

“… Oi, why’s there nothing but one entrance, passage, and room?”
“My plan was to get a monster first! I heard that was the strongest way.”
“H-hey, in other words, those bandits inside the dungeon, they’re… monsters? Is that alright?”
“Ah, those are intruders!”

Right? Even looking at the Dungeon Map, there’s enemy-ish indicators on it.

“Rather—what is this place!? Aren’t we in a dungeon!?”
“This is the Master Room inside the Dungeon Core. A-a different dimension? Kind of?”
“You… in other words, inside you?”
“Ah, un. Like inside my true body… eh, what? You said that so indecently… perv.”

Rokuko’s cheeks blushed slightly as she looked at me with reproachful eyes. That’s a false accusation. I want to demand an apology and compensation. But let’s confirm something important first.

“From what I see, the dungeon core in a room that the bandits hang out in?”
“That’s how it looks to me…”
“… Why?”
“Eh, Dungeon Cores have to be inside the dungeon or they don’t work you know? That’s common sense.”

I’m getting a headache.
Dungeon Cores have to be installed inside their dungeon or they have no effect.
There’s only one room in the dungeon.
Therefore, the Dungeon Core is installed in that room.
And there are about eight bandits inside the room that has the Dungeon Core in it.

“… Ummm? This, isn’t this checkmate? It’s goodbye right off the bat?”
“That’s why I used the last of my DP to summon a monster and kick the bandits out. Then Kehma appeared. A weakling appearing was definitely a mistake, but I don’t think I can send you back…”
“Yeah, so even though I want to go back to my world it’s no good?”
“Impossible. Well, it’s not like it’s absolutely impossible since I was able to summon you, but it’d probably take way too much DP?”

DP stands for dungeon points. [They’re able to do lots of stuff!]—is what I’m told.
Well then it’s good for now.
I’m the Dungeon Master, but I wonder what’d happen if the Dungeon Core got destroyed?

“Well, you’ll die you know? Since the master and core are partners in body and mind, we’d be sharing lots.”
“Dying would be bad…”
“It’s alright, even if the master dies, the core will be fine.”
“Then isn’t that ‘two as one’ thing just a one way road!?”
“Ah, un, though well, it’s alright, I haven’t died yet. Un.”
“How!?”
“It’s been ten days since the bandits made this cave their base, but they haven’t done anything like trying to destroy the Dungeon Core.”
“… Eh?”

By the way, the Dungeon Core was about the size of a basketball. It was always glowing, lighting up the walls and floor of the room. It’s unlikely for there to be a situation like one where the bandits wouldn’t see it. Rather, that’s what makes it so prominent.

“… That’s why it’s alright. Besides, it’s a small amount, but I get DP from there being intruders.”

Is that really safe?
No, it probably isn’t. That’s why she tried summoning a monster by using DP.

“… Got it. By the way, how do you get more DP?”
“Well…”

Summing it all up:

Natural recovery from the earth vein. (This is the basic 10 DP per day)
Maintaining the state of having an intruder in the dungeon. (Depends on the strength of intruder)
Killing an intruder. (Depends on the strength of the intruder)
Offering a corpse. (Depends on the original strength of the corpse)
Offering treasure. (Depends on the treasure)

That’s how it is.
By the way, it seems to cost 20 DP to summon a goblin.
You’d normally be able to summon one every other day, but with the eight bandits lodging in the dungeon for the past ten days, that’s apparently +80 DP more per day.

Well, with the 900 DP gained during these ten days that the bandits have controlled the cave and adding it together with the other 100 DP, it made up the 1,000 DP she used on monster gacha.
I see, so she hoped that since it cost fifty times more than a goblin it would be stronger than fifty goblins huh. But gacha has fails too. Rather, I’m like the consolation prize. Well, it’s called gacha but that’s probably just it being automatically translated… this seems super complicated.
Additionally, there are some several ranks of slots: 100, 1000, 10000… it goes up by a factor of ten each time, with no upper limit. The 1000 DP slots I came from was the second from the cheapest.
It’s rumored that goblins can come from the 10000 DP gacha and a dragon from the 1000 DP one. The probably improves with the cost, so I guess it’s basically a luck game?

“Why aren’t you a dragon!”
“Well, it wouldn’t be off even if a goblin appeared, aren’t you aiming too high?”

This blonde loli’s ego is some next level stuff. Does she think that she’s the center of the universe? Something that convenient doesn’t actually happen. I mean, look at me. I just wanted to sleep but got summoned into another world to be put to work.

“… The remaining DP is… 9?”

Did she spin the gacha as soon as she reached 1000 DP? We’re flat-out broke.
I took a look at the catalog from the DP part of the menu, but I couldn’t even summon a goblin with just 9 DP.
Dragons? Even the weakest kind starts at 100,000 DP, young lady. Haha, someone that’s wanting to get something like that is too much of an idiot.
When I took a look at the everyday items page, there were a few things I could get with 9 DP.

“Alright, I’ve decided.”
“What are you going to do, Kehma?”

Using up 5 DP, I summoned a [Buckwheat Pillow].

“I’m going to sleep.”
“Eh, wai—!?”
“While I sleep, please keep quiet. Night.”

Yep, this really is convenient. Next thing I’m going to summon is a [Futon].
It takes 10,000 DP for a [Heavenly Pillow] and 100,000 DP for a [Top Quality Futon].
When I laid down and closed my eyes, her yapping voice slowly faded out.

Ch04 - Let’s Deal With the Bandits Somehow

Two days passed since I was summoned.
Somehow or another my DP is even 179, no, it’s 180 now. I could summon nine goblins.
By the way, I know the reason why the dungeon core wasn’t destroyed. They used it as a hot water bottle.
The dungeon core shined faintly and was slightly warm.
The bandits’ boss made the dungeon core room his bed, I understood when he put his feet up on the dungeon core and fell asleep. As expected, when I wanted to see how things were going outside, I pulled up the app and saw the dirty soles of his feet on the wall.
He kicked dungeon core-san in the heart.

“W-well? Even I can earn DP if it’s these guys? It’s a win-win you know? Fufun.”

Knowing that her heart was being rolled around by some smelly feet, the blonde-haired loli dungeon core was almost in tears. I saw something adorable.

“Now then, is there anything to do…”
“Summon something! Summon goblins for a slaughter!? Ah, a 150 DP lizardman would be good! That guy would never forgive that boss, he’ll stab him over and over!”
“Idiot. Someone like that would just be stabbed instead.”

Seems that she was humiliated by her heart being treated like a heater after all.

“There are eight enemies, our war potential is overwhelmingly insufficient. If you didn’t summon a goblin to begin with, we would have saved a bit more on food expenses.”
“Hmph, I didn’t know about that guy’s maintenance costs… wait, didn’t you also use some of the DP to summon a [Futon]!?”

And another thing, it seems you can see anywhere inside the dungeon from the dungeon core. It was a function of the menu.
By the way, Rokuko didn’t know that. That makes sense, since it wasn’t a needed feature if you only had a single room.

“But, what do we do?”
“Ah, what… hey, what about letters? Can Rokuko write? Can the bandits read?”
“If that’s it… Yea, I can write. I wonder if the bandits can’t read? They seemed to read a book of their spoils, so if it’s easy.”
“I see. Then, please write down what I say out loud for a sec.”
“Oka~y.”

♦ ♦ ♦

“Booooss! Please wake up!”
“Ngah…?”

When the bandit boss woke up in the cave, there was a box.
Was something like this here yesterday? No, there wasn’t. I would have noticed it before.

“What’s this? How’d it get here?”
“I dunno. But Rodriguez was on guard and said no one came in.”
“So what, did this just appear out of thin air?”
“So… what now?”

I checked the box, but it doesn’t look like there are traps set on it. When I carefully opened the box, there was a steel helmet in it.
This is a good item, and new at that.

“Hey, isn’t this pretty good? Seems like it’d sell for a lot. I might even use it.”
“Boss, there’s something written on the bottom of the box.”
“Hm? What’s this shit… writing? Oi! Braken, you should be able to read these, read em!”
“Yah! Lesseee?”

Showing the box to his underling to read it, it was read.
The content was unexpected.

[I–am–the–danjun–cor. Thank–you–for–defeating–goblins. This–is–a–gift. If–there’s–more–done, I–can–give–more.]

“Dungeon core…? Oi, this is a dungeon?”
“Eh, no, this place was called an [Ordinary Cave].”
“Ah, hold up boss! When I was an adventurer I heard this dungeon was named [Ordinary Cave]!”
“Is that true Johnny!?”

The bandit boss was startled.
There was something glittering from the ground, the warmth felt good when he placed his feet on it. Perhaps, was that the dungeon core?
He hadn’t heard of being able to talk with dungeon cores, but this was a letter from the dungeon core. To say this was someone’s trick… no one came in even with someone standing watch, and there’s this steel helmet no one could have prepared.
And according to the letter, the steel helmet seems to be a gift for defeating the goblins.
Perhaps it was the goblins near the dungeon core that he kicked out when he came to the cave. For a bandit boss, five goblins were nothing but small fry. To get a steel helmet like this just for beating some small fry…
“Oi oi are you serious…? I see my luck’s turning around…!”

Stories of dungeons are famous. There’s a dungeon called [White Labyrinth] in the imperial capital.
No, the imperial capital was made where the dungeon was already at after all.
As for the dungeon, there were monsters, but it was a place that produced various treasures, like magic armor. And this is a dungeon. However, there haven’t been any monsters so far. If I had to say anything, there were just the five goblins when we came here. And then there’s this treasure. This steel helmet.

“It seems I pleased this dungeon.”

The bandit boss grinned.
The dungeon produced treasure for the person who pleased it… in other words, it was the same as holding infinite riches.
[If there’s more done, I can give more.]
Come to think of it, the goblin corpses had disappeared before they realized it. They thought someone’s subordinate cleaned it up though…
So that means, in other words, it was something like that.
The box that had contained the steel helmet also disappeared before they realized it.

♦ ♦ ♦

“Whyyyyyyyyyy!! Him-! Why-! Why did we reward someone like that guy-!?”

The blonde-haired loli was writhing about.
[Pen and Ink] was 5 DP, [Wooden Box] was 5 DP, and [High Quality Steel Helm] was 170 DP.
And spending the DP I had, we’re broke at 0 DP now.
I used all of the DP to give a [Present] to the bandit’s boss.

“Why!? It wouldn’t have been very difficult to summon goblins!”
“Then die when they fail? Hahaha, sorry. I don’t want to die yet. I want to sleep.”
“T-that’s why, you’re… a, a traitor!”
“We’ve gained some time with this for now. Since we’ll massacre them before long, calm down.”
“Eh?”

Maybe because she was astonished that the word massacre came out of my mouth, but Rokuko exposed a goofy face.

“Why? You, since you’re human, didn’t you give a tribute in order to help them?”
“Hah? I just want to be safe in my bed. Even so, why should I leave dangerous guys like bandits alone?”
“Eeh… we-well then, shouldn’t you be hesitating in taking care of people of the same race?”
“I don’t know. I want to sleep. Besides, that doesn’t mean I’ll take care of them directly… Ah, since there’s nothing left to do today I’m going to sleep. Alright, good night.”

I took out the futon and laid down.

“W-w-wait up! Please explain a bit more!”
“It can’t be helped huh… then I’ll explain some more. Tomorrow. Good night.”
“D-don’t slee–!? …!”

As I fell asleep, I heard Rokuko’s voice fade out.
It seems the order from the first day is still effective. Good night.

Ch06 - Let’s Use Magic for the First Time

Since I ran out of DP by adding rooms, I also ran out of things to do.
That didn’t change even after I slept and woke up again. I still didn’t have enough DP…

On that subject, what of the restroom and my meals? I’ll say this.
I eat three meals a day, each set of bread and water (5 DP). By the way, the bread that comes out isn’t hard brown bread. I can choose from pastries or simple prepared breads. I choose the largest portion of bread whenever possible and share it with the goblin to eat.
Though next is the restroom, it’s the corner of the room… Well, I should have toilet paper prepared and have it partitioned off right? However, it can’t be helped since I don’t leave the master room.
Since the dungeon core absorbs all of the trash and excrement without even leaving a smell behind, I’m really thankful. Rokuko puts on a reluctant expression when she absorbs poop though.

“… How would you like to watch someone poop in your heart, oi?”
“Hahaha, a girl saying something as improper as poop. Isn’t it fine? There’s also goblin poop, isn’t Rokuko’s goblin fetish crying from happiness?”
“Hey, do you really think that about me!? Do you even see me as intelligent life!?”
“Oh, well, an enigmatic creature… kind of. Oh, but I have said before that just your feet are highly rated. They have a light complexion and absolutely healthy.”
“Nooo this master is scary.”

Even so, I haven’t been in a tub or entered a shower to bathe in several days.
I wonder if my hair is going to start smelling soon… then I saw the goblin next to me. It had its ugly face and large fangs as usual. Clothes? It wore just a rag wrapped around its waist. A wild style.
If such a wild guy were neglected for a few days wouldn’t he start to smell like a dog? … Is what I thought. However, he was clean. Does he have some kind of secret?

“Oh, I used the life magic [Cleanup] on him.”

It was magic. Right, this is a fantasy world.

“Magic huh, if it’s magic there’s no helping it then. Then could you use it on me as well?”
“Eh, you want me to clean you?”
“… Oh, the goblin gets better treatment because of your goblin fetish huh.”
“That’s not it! I didn’t know the dungeon master wanted [Cleanup]! Rather, use it on yourself!”
“No no no, what’s with the assumption I can use magic?”
“Eh, you can’t use it?”

According to her, everyone seems to be able to use magic. Even humans.
Even the bandits used it when I wasn’t watching…
Can I use it too? I’ll ask how to use it.

“Just charge magic power and simply use [Cleanup].”

I don’t get it at all. What do she mean by ‘charge magic power’? ‘Simply use [Cleanup]’ she says. She’s the kind of person that wouldn’t write down how many teaspoons or grams of salt to use in the recipe book. I’m not one of this world’s magic humans, oi! Even beginners are beginners!

“… Kehma, can’t you use the menu? It’s the same thing as that alright?”
“Seriously? [Cleanup]… Oh, it worked.”

Along with the sensation of being completely covered by a membrane of carbonated water starting at my feet, my body was cleaned.
With this, I’m free to sleep in peace of mind that my body is clean. I’ll use it immediately after waking up so that I can feel refreshed and go back to sleep comfortably.
I wonder if something like MP is expended? There’s even a pleasant tired feeling. Isn’t this the most optimal magic in order to sleep? This is wonderful.

“By the way, though manifesting life magic only requires a mental image and magic power, those aren’t the only requirements. For stronger ones it’s no good unless you use scrolls to memorize them you know?”
“Scroll…?”
“Yeah, though you can theoretically learn to manifest it by yourself, that’s at an [Unrealistic and Impossible] level. That’s what researchers are for. Well, I normally learn magic by using scrolls. I don’t have any to use though… Ah, aren’t they in the DP catalog?”

Examining it when she said that, there were treasures and items like [Scroll of Fire Ball (500 DP)] and [Scroll of Ice Barrier (700 DP)].
The attributes were the standard four elements: earth, water, wind, and fire. There seemed to be special attributes like light, darkness, and space-time as well.
Furthermore, they were each divided into ranks: bottom class, low class, middle class, upper class, top class, emperor class, and divine class. Fire Ball seemed to be classified as low class fire attribute magic.
Meanwhile, I’m interested on this middle class earth attribute magic.

[Scroll of Create Golem (10000 DP)]

I’m very interested. If I use this, wouldn’t I have a servant that’ll do whatever I say?
Well, even Rokuko is in a servant-like state that she does whatever I say. All the same, since I’d feel awkward if it’s a little girl, I want something like a robot.
Though I want that item soon, I wonder if I should go with that or use that DP for the [Heavenly Pillow]…

Ch07 - The Bandits’ Boss

In the end, two days passed by uneventfully since I added more rooms.
The bandits seems to have taken a vacation and spent all of their time in the dungeon, half of them laying down drinking sake. I thought they’d attack travelers and merchants every day, bit it seems I was wrong. They were taking a holiday while their boss was out overnight, I wonder what he’s doing?
Well, it’s fine though since thanks to that I got a lot of DP with just that little.

Well, the boss came back with seven more thugs.
Though I guess he invited them from somewhere, their strength… even if I calculate the DP backwards from coming in, they’re just thugs after all.
One person was roughly between 10-15 DP per day, so seven more people increases the daily income by around 70-105 DP? Simply delicious. In addition to that, when they went out they came back with a young person that was probably an adventurer.
Yep, gagged and tied with rope, it was a woman.
They started stabbing the young person with their swords as I thought that. These people are scary.
When the slaughter finished, they watched the pool of blood be absorbed by the dungeon in mute amazement.

“Oh, a decent amount of DP came in. 300 DP huh.”
“… Goblin Lover Rokuko, don’t summon fifteen goblins.”

Oh yeah. It was a present to the dungeon, yeah. Wasn’t their effort good? Let’s reward them…
So, since it seems that it took a considerable amount of time for them to stab the adventurer to death, I decided to give them a sharp iron sword (150 DP). 520 DP left. I want to save up more…

“Hey, I wanted you to add something like more rooms ya know?”

Seeing this, even though the bandit’s boss had the sword in his hand, he complained while dissatisfied.
What’s with you, even though I took great pains to bless you with a sword.

“Haah, say that earlier, whatever.”
“What now? Going to make a room?”
“I don’t feel like using more DP… ah, that’s right.”

♦ ♦ ♦

Going to town, I went to sell the plundered goods.
Well, even though I say that I went to town, more precisely I went to a slum around the outer wall.
As I expected, public order wasn’t so bad that a bandit boss like me could go inside the walls… it’d be different if I did a bit of bribing though.
Ah, about the steel helmet I got from the dungeon, I decided to not sell it and use it. It’s probably good to take care of something like a first present.
Well, I obtained seven new companions from the street.
Street thugs, people in my profession, runaway slaves… well, everyone gives off that kind of feeling.
While I was at it, I attacked and stunned a brat adventurer who was walking along the path, bringing them back to the base.
Hahaha, it really is a dangerous place away from the city. Rookies shouldn’t come to the mountainside by themselves ya know.
Because of that, I took put it in the dungeon for it to make another room, feeding it the corpse. The seven new companions had surprised faces when they saw a stiff being completely eaten by the ground.

“Boss, a box came out!”
“Ooh… wait, what’s this? A sword?”

A sword was put into the box.
An iron sword. The item was a better quality than I’d used so far.
But, that isn’t what I want right now. I want a room.
As expected, with seven more people it’s cramped. Well, it was six people in a small room before. Thinking about the two people rotating out to stand guard, entering the rooms that were increased to three was cramped. I want a new room soon.

When I mumbled that, a new box came out.

“Yeah, what is it this time?”

Taking the box, [Since it wasn’t enough to make a new room, make one yourself] was written on the bottom of it.
Inside were three brand new pickaxes.

Ch09 - Let’s Use DP

“What’s this, so good! [Melon Bread] is stupidly good! Kehma, you eat delicious things like this!?”

The slovenly dungeon core seemed anxious about the melon bread, taking a bite of it. She scoffed up this rest of it with sparkling eyes.
You can eat bread? I mean you can eat things? That’s the first time I saw it.

“W-what? Even I can eat food!”
“But, isn’t it unneeded?
“Though that’s right, it’s a luxury. Luxuries… isn’t there more?”

As far as this goes, it’s 5 DP for one you know? For a set of drinks that is.
Since it comes with an assortment of six sweet rolls, it was haughty to ask for a set.
No, I also gave the bandits a bread assortment. She didn’t notice.
Additionally, since it was a cheap 5 DP for a barrel of beverages… it felt considerably overpriced…
“Well, there are various kinds of bread, but we wouldn’t be saving DP…”
“I-isn’t it ok? We have 2000 now you know? S-so, i-if we use just a little…”

Ah, her eyes were serious.

“You even used it on your own to buy a [Pillow] and a [Futon]! Isn’t a little for me fine!?”
“Even though I gave you a goblin~?”
“Wha-! G-Gobsuke has nothing to do with this! Besides, doesn’t Kehma use 20 DP every day for food to eat!”

When did you name it!? That’s news to me!

“Rather, I give the goblin half of my meal. The goblin actually costs more than 20 DP due to maintenance costs… rather isn’t he a good-for-nothing with our present condition? He’s comple~tely your pet now right?”
“T-that’s not it! Gobsuke can be helpful! Right, Gobsuke!?”

The subject suddenly changed, Gobsuke stared blankly in puzzlement with a [Eh? What, why did this the conversation shift?].
I wondered, it felt like the fangs jutting out under it’s nose looked made it’s face look doggish.
… Would it eat dog food?

“Whatever. Honestly, I don’t mind as long as you don’t use too much… anyway, if we each buy drink and bread assortments from now on, our DP expenditure won’t change.”

That probably suppressed her, seeing as how she fell silent.

“Yay! Then get a bread assortment out at once!”
“Couldn’t you have gotten them yourself? You’ve also used DP from the menu right?”
“Eh? But, I’ve never seen [Assortment of Bread] or [Melon Bread] before you know? …Huh, there’s more? O~h, I can choose from [Black Bread], [White Bread] and [Melon Bread]! I didn’t know!”

Hm? What?

“Oi, say your choices again.”
“Eh? The three things are [Black Bread] [White Bread] and [Melon Bread]?”
“… … That’s it?”
“? Yeah, but what do you mean?”

For my [Bread Assortment (5 DP)]… the choices are [Cream-filled Roll] [Bean Paste Roll] [Jam Roll] [Steamed Roll] [Apple Pie] [Deep-fried Bread], changing the DP.

“Do you know what this is?”
“… Bread, right? What’s this, it’s the first time I’ve seen it shaped like this. I mean, the bread Kehma produces is wrapped in something transparent, can I eat that?”
“No, you don’t eat it. You tear the plastic open and eat what’s inside… by the way, this is called a [Bean Paste Roll]. Try it.”
“Eeeh, so this is called a [Bean Paste Roll]… nom…~~~! So good! [Bean Paste Rolls] are also amazing! Eeeh, there’s yellow stuff inside. Ooh, so good! What’s this, so good-”

I thought of something and had passed her a [Cream-filled Roll].

“Rokuko, look at the bread assortment menu again and see if your choices increased or not.”
“Eh? ‘Kay… There’s more. [Bean Paste Roll] was added. Eeeh, so something like this can happen too.”
“So next, take out a [Bean Paste Roll]. You can mix it with the melon bread.”
“Really!? Fufufu, then, half and half, three of each… fufu, fufufu!”
“Yeah, I’m taking a [Bean Paste Roll].”
“AAAAAAAH!?”

Incidentally, when Rokuko took out the [Bread Assortment], I took a [Bean Paste Roll]… Yeah, that’s a [Cream-filled Roll]. Even the way it looked, it was a [Cream-filled Roll]. Additionally, it wasn’t reproduced with the plastic and was bare.

“Sorry, Rokuko. That was a [Cream-filled Roll]. This one is a [Bean Paste Roll].”
“Eh, really? Heeh, so this is a [Bean Paste Roll]. Hehe, this one is red on the inside! … Super sweet! I love this one too! The genuine [Bean Paste Roll] is amazing!”

Sorry for deceiving you again. That’s a [Jam Roll]. Strawberry jam.

“It’s fine to take out another. Make it four [Cream-filled Rolls] and two [Bean Paste Rolls] this time.”
“What this, you want to please me that much? Aaah mou, Kehma is shining today! Four [Cream-filled Rolls] and two [Bean Paste Rolls]!”
“… Oh, what were your choices?”
“Eh? Ah, now that you mention it they increased again… Alright, I brought them out you know? Is it okay to eat them?”

Seeing what Rokuko exchanged DP for, there were four [Cream-filled Rolls] and two [Jam Rolls].
… I see.
Apparently, it seems the DP menu’s priority is what the person themselves recognizes.
And likely, [What you don’t know isn’t on the menu].
Just looking to make sure, other than the missing plastic, only the name was incorrect.
Did she absorb it or something? Ah, that’s not it, but she does absorb trash every day… is it recognition after all?
Nevertheless, there’s a high possibility it’s not limited to things that exist in this world.
I’ve never seen a dragon even though it’s on the menu… though it could be a default thing for a dungeon master.
Though I wanted to verify it a little more, it became a hassle. I didn’t want to waste DP either.

“It’s okay to eat right? Right?”
“Yeah, go for it… Alright, since that’s enough for four days, eat it carefully yeah? Split it with Gobsuke.”
“Hae-!?”

Biting into a [Cream-filled Roll], Rokuko froze.
Don’t worry, even if you finish eating them today, I’ll share mine with Gobsuke. Though I won’t say it.

Ch10 - The Bandit Bought Slaves

Two days after the bandits lost five newcomers, the bandit’s boss lead some newcomers in with him.
A whopping eighteen people… Since the seven new guys were reduced by five, that with the other eight it became ten in total. So with these new guys, twenty-eight, a 2.8x increase in one go. Where’s he getting them from… as I thought that, I noticed two were attacking adventurers that had been tied up to be used as sacrifices. Well, even with that, that’s still twenty-six. Isn’t this already the scale of a small village?

“Oh, other than those two sacrifices they’re all slaves.”
“How do know that? … Ah, the collars? Well, two sacrifices… okay, guess I’ll add two rooms in the back. As you’d expect, it’s a priority to make sure they fit so we can get the DP…”

Looking from above, I added a room shaped like a square in the upper right side.
Rather, is it okay for slaves to be sold to bandits in this world?

“I’d heard that humans who commit crimes are turned into criminal slaves, but…”
“So the bandits are buying returned criminals eh? That’s a draining basket…”

Well, they were obviously non-combatants…there were women, or rather little girls.
In this world, there’s no reason to look filthy since there’s life magic.
… Yep, their eyes were full of malice and they were nearly nude. Heck, wasn’t the slave the boss had obviously in the single digit age range? So they bought a child with eyes like a dead fish like that. Will he raise her as his daughter? Oi, she even has dog ears… wait, oi.

She is a sex slave.

You lolicon! Coming here with this R18 development! Well, it was only men till now…
Stripping the scant rags off of her, he used the magic Cleanup while suspiciously stroking her body with his hands. He stuck his face onto her with a dirty sound, pushing her down onto the bed… ah, yep. Cut.
She has eyes like a dead fish. Perfectly a Doll-san.

“Wooow… wooooow, amazing…. I didn’t know humans could still have reproductive behaviors with such a small body, wo-… I-is Kehma aiming for me!?”
“No, I don’t like forcing people. To begin with, someone small like you isn’t in my strike zone! I’m not a lolicon!”
“B-but you evaluate feet right? Mine, as well as that human slave’s.”
“Her bare feet are all tattered, even though they have such a good shape, it’s a waste. Damn, I’d like to at least have her wear some socks.”

… If possible, knee socks would be good. White knee socks, black knee socks. Maybe not knee socks, but a collar and stockings to match that important part of a dog, the dog ears? … Oi, erase the filthy bandits that are on the screen.

“I get the feeling it’ll be ten minutes at most…”
“Don’t pay them any attention. Well, I’m going to go lay down… The DP we got from the sacrifices this time was pretty good.”

♦ ♦ ♦

What’s so good about being a bandit…
I can’t enter a town normally, and shopping costs even more with a middleman.
Though I talk to the peddlers to not break our cover, they take advantage and raise the prices.
We have to do amateur repairs on our weapons ourselves since we can’t even go to a blacksmith, so we just use crushing weapons. Thinking about my weapon breaking while I’m using it sends shivers down my spine.
Gold. Our lives are consumed by gaining it. Though I say that, it’s better than risking your life as a mercenary.

However, strength can steal anything.
Though the income isn’t stable, the returns are huge.
Moreover, in my time as a mercenary I heard it was possible to join something called the Hidden Guild.
Don’t attack wagons that had the Hidden Guild’s mark, that was the rule. But there many merits.
You could get anything so long as you had the money… well, it was expensive though.
One thing is the brothel… though it was nothing but a tent in the slum, it had women.
Since bandits obviously couldn’t enter the town, we can’t go to normal brothels. But sexual desire builds up. Adventurers are nothing but men, and women adventurers only succeed since they gather attention and are hard to attack. Therefore, we can’t help but get the assistance of the Hidden Guild’s prostitutes.

Even a bandit’s boss has to come to the Hidden Guild’s brothel for that.
Though they didn’t have satisfactory women, we could only gaze at the feet of the average high-quality downtown brothel with the price.
Still, you can’t buy a good woman without the money for it.
… It’s just better to buy one. With that thought, the bandit’s boss bought the cheapest woman.

A demi-human child that wasn’t even in the two-digit age range came out. Not even human. The Hidden Guild’s cheapest prostitute didn’t have clothes and only had a slave collar.
Not even trained, it didn’t know what to do by itself.
Though if this one’s ears and tail were cut off it would look closer to a human, even that wasn’t done. Most likely, it would have been a bother to pay for a demi-human slave to be treated by recovery magic, or maybe just for someone’s eccentrics. If you didn’t use recovery magic, she would be in danger of dying… are corpses preferable?
But it was too small to begin with. It was ridiculous for her to call herself a prostitute like that.
Though the fruit was immature, a woman was a woman. Grasping its delicate arm that seemed like it would break from contact, I took her.
The feeling wasn’t bad. Rather, the young and smooth skin was reminiscent of the luxury brothel’s prostitute that I was taken to by a senior in my times as a mercenary. It was arousing.

After the act, the bandit’s boss decided to begin buying crime slaves.
The Hidden Guild dealt with slaves of all kinds. Dying slaves were cheap, healthy slaves were expensive.
Killing adventurers reduces the number of newcomers I have, so it’ll be better to get crime slaves that have experience killing. That’s what the bandit’s boss was thinking.
Sooner or later my underlings will also need sex slaves… though sex slaves are more expensive than crime slaves, it can’t be helped since they’re luxury items. Let’s buy some if there’s a bit of left over funds.
The bandit’s boss lined up the slaves he’d bought. The demi-human child he bought in the brothel was lined up as well. Though he felt the money previously spent in the brothel before buying this would be wasted, since they were cheap, he decided to buy them. They were also priced dirt cheap. Or rather, they were almost for free, a bonus for taking other slaves as well. He’d wondered if they were about to be disposed of, their prices were cheaper than ten pieces of tough black bread.
He comfortably caressed the child slave that was almost free of charge… remembering the reminiscent feel of the high class prostitute, the bandit’s boss felt that he’d profited.
As long as it became yours, you didn’t need to worry about a penalty price for breaking or ripping it up. It was your responsibility to widen unusable holes and cut off the tail and ears.

“… Should I wait to cut off its ears and tail till it grows up a bit? It’d be a waste for it to die after going through so much trouble. I want the original at least.”

Carrying the sluggish demi-human child that walked slowly, the bandit’s boss headed toward the [Ordinary Cave].
On the way, we attacked a pair of adventurers we noticed from behind, capturing them alive.
That was good. With this we might have another room to put the slaves in.

“I’m so lucky!”

Kuku, the bandit’s boss laughed.

Ch11 - The End of the Bandits

It’s been a week since the adventurers attacked. That means the dungeon was peaceful.
Adventurers haven’t come, so the bandits are uninjured.
The bandits left and brought back corpses twice this past week. The four corpses turned into around 600 DP. It was most likely too difficult to capture them alive.
… Though I really did think that, isn’t that poor earnings for twenty-six people? Well, one of them is a non-combat child.
Ah, their reward? I decided to wait a few days since they hadn’t killed inside the cave. There’s no rush you know?

By the way, the boss plays around with the dog-eared girl every day… that’s the only part I don’t find peaceful.
Even if she’s a slave or something, as a Japanese, I can’t just suddenly adjust and accept it.
Rather than the other slaves serving the bandits, just one of them became a plaything.
Is it a small relief that, other than the boss, no one made a move on her?
It seems his underlings’ evaluations of him is something like [The boss is a lolicon]. After being asked if he would buy more adult female slaves, he said they’d get them by raiding.

“… Still, he doesn’t get tired of doing it day after day…”
“It’s becoming an eyesore now.”
“I had a hunch he was a good guy, but guess I imagined it~…”

However, Rokuko might actually have a lot of human characteristics, pouting over a girl being made into a plaything.

“Oi… I don’t like them contaminating the dungeon with their body fluids… it’s annoying.”
“Ah, that? … Though it’s okay for me to use the master room as a restroom?”
“Yeah, it’s fine if it’s Kehma or Gobsuke, it can’t be helped… I did more or less summon you as monsters.”
“I’m considered a monster too? … Now that you mention it, I was summoned huh.”
“It feels like you’re just going in circles. Don’t be so easygoing… moreover, oi, is there no way to get them to leave?”
“With that tone, your hobby is definitely scat. But your goblin and scat hobbies are bad.”
“I’m not aroused by excrement you know!? Kehma is also misunderstanding that thing with the goblin you know!?”

Yeah, it was fiddling around with Rokuko yesterday.
It seems like… today is the day the dungeon’s peace will be broken.
No, the time for peace has arrived, maybe.

“Ah, something amazing is coming…”

Hearing Rokuko mutter something to herself, I pulled up the map.
Map of the surrounding area… As long as it’s within view distance from the dungeon, I can see detailed geographic information and features. On it were red dots signifying enemies, marching forward in well-regulated rows.

“About thirty people huh… they finally came. Were they early? Or slow…?”
“Who’s coming? Those guys?”
“Yeah, it’s probably the suppression group. And looking at how fast they’re progressing, they’re a trained group. The knights… will probably be the end of the bandits. Though unlikely, it’d be delicious if they survived.”

And it seems that the bandits noticed. Taking out the semi-transparent monitor from the menu, I decided to check out what the bandits were doing.
It really is convenient since it could be used as though there were surveillance cameras installed in the dungeon.
When I looked, underlings were reporting to the boss in a panic.

[Boss, it’s bad, knights! They’re coming our way!]
[What!? How were we exposed, we killed everyone that saw our base!?]

The bandit’s boss panicked. It seems he didn’t think that knights would be dispatched for them.

[No, they’re human but having said that they’re knights, it’s better to not be killed… how many?]
[S-sorry, I came back as soon as I saw them wearing armor. At least, err, more than five people!]
[Tch, can’t be helped then… well, we’re going to ambush them in the dungeon even if there’s more or less of ’em anyway.]
[That so?]
[If there’s a small amount we’ll use a surprise attack, if there’s a lot of ’em we’ll fence them in from the outside. The End.]
[Ooh! I see, as expected of the boss! Alright, everyone heard him! Let’s ambush ’em!]
[[[ YEAH! ]]]

Apparently it looks like they’re motivated; more so, inside the dungeon.
That’s very convenient. It’s good that I taught the bandit boss how to fight using the exits and passages for ambushes this week. It’s really good he isn’t bright enough to escape from here.

“Then, can the bandits win?”
“Though it depends on the strength of the knights… if the strength of those thirty are like the recent adventurers, they’ll be wiped out for sure.”

I also checked out how the group of knights were doing.
I decided to watch until they completed the long-awaited annihilation of the bandits. Since it’s happening also due to the results of my work.
As for the bandits, eight were in the entrance room, with eight people on the way to the core room. It seems the ambush will be in the core room with nine people, including the bandit boss. Though they distributed their forces, the rooms limited how many could actually perform an ambush.
When the bandits finished their ambush preparations, the knights arrived at the cave entrance.

[Full stop. Henry-dono, is this the [Ordinary Cave]?]
[Yes. Most likely, that is the bandits’ hideout… Beck, I leave it to you.]
[Yeah. Thanks for cooperating… Life, return the beats to my wave–[Life Search].]

A knight wearing full body armor used the skill. After a moment, a transparent wave extended around the knight using the skill… Judging by its name, it looks like it’s a skill that searches for living things. I wonder if it uses the principles of echolocation?
At least with this, the bandits’ ambush will lose its effect.

[Hmm… from what I heard, there are at least eight people that way. They’re preparing to ambush us.]

There certainly were eight bandits waiting in the first room.
… Maybe he can’t hear what’s beyond the wooden door? Or maybe it’s the effective range?

[That’s it for the information.]
[Alright, let’s commence the bandit suppression. Though it doesn’t look like there are any prisoners… as a precaution, we’ll use a sleeping drug.]
[Understood!]
[Five people stay and watch the attack from the outside. The rest, surround the entrance. Kill any escaping bandits.]
[Roger that.]

The group of knights surrounded the cave’s exit, taking position. They began to burn an incense at the entrance.
… So that’s how it is? Well, that makes it unnecessary to purposely walk into an ambush.
After the incense burned for a while, it was time for the bandits to move.
When they started to smell the aroma of the incense, they weren’t able to endure the drowsiness and collapsed.

[Gu, this is… it’s a sleeping drug! R-run, get to the back room!]
[No, we should attack before we can’t move! They won’t have many people if they used a trick like this. Let’s go!]
[If we shut the door, the smoke… ugu-… w-what do we do…]
[Hmph, cowards, you go and sleep. I’m going to kill them all!]

One of the new guys from before that had finished off the adventurers in the cave, becoming top brass, headed out of the cave with five desperate slaves.
The only guy to remain, not collapsed from drowsiness, was the guy who suggested to withdraw… he was crouching and hitting his abdomen.
As for the six who went outside, their fighting strength dropped due to drowsiness. They couldn’t do anything against the swords of the knights that encircled the entrance. They threw their blunt swords in desperation, though it was easily deflected by the knights’ armors.
Listening to his comrades’ shrieks outside, he mumbled [Ahh, I wasn’t wrong…]. He fell asleep with the other eight there, collapsing.
His definitive mistake was to become a comrade of the bandits to begin with, but it didn’t seem he noticed that.

Though the smell thinned, they couldn’t tell when it came to the point where it wouldn’t put them to sleep, so the knights used [Life Search] again.

[[Life Search]… Hmm, there are two left for now.]
[Alright… the passage is narrow. We’ll go in in rows of two. Be careful.]

The knights entered the dungeon one after another… However, that the knights took up positions outside the cave meant that they already knew that the inside of the dungeon was a dungeon.
Yep, it was correct for us to expand it. Otherwise the DP from those six people dying would have been wasted.

[… Alright, two bandits left. Be sure to finish them off.]
[Is that alright?]
[We can’t turn back at this point. Besides, it’s our job to raze the bandit hideout. If we crush the head, it’ll be fine to leave the rest to adventurers… Look, we’re still far from the back. There are probably people better than the underlings arranged at the entrance farther inside… Though it’d be nice if we already defeated the boss earlier.]
[Indeed.]

When they decapitated the two sleeping bandits, DP came in.
Feeling my clothes being tugged on, I looked at Rokuko. She had a strange look on her face.

“Is it fine to not take the corpses from a bit ago? It’s wasteful.”
“… You absolutely can’t absorb them you know? If you did that we wouldn’t be able to deceive them anymore.”
“Deceive them?”
“… Once they know that this is a dungeon that eats people, or that this beginner dungeon gained energy, they might consider this dungeon is dangerous and destroy the core. Though I more or less have insurance…”
“Uu, I’ll die if the core gets destroyed… Insurance? What is it?”
“… Hey, remember the goblin room I made a while ago?”
“Ooh, the area you made a bit away! It was the dummy [Ordinary Cave] right?”
“Yeah. Since this world doesn’t have very accurate maps, we can probably deceive them even if the cave’s position shifts somewhat… maybe, well, it’s possible they’ll accept it and misunderstand that this cave is an ordinary cave. That’s just a small hope though…”
“Un un, I see… Huh? What about the core?”

In fact, by placing a dummy core, the castling function… though I want to save the function that could instantly switch it with the genuine dungeon core in case of an emergency (It can be used even if an intruder is in the core room), there was no choice. Since it cost 5000 DP, we couldn’t take this out till yesterday. Nevertheless, it’s the type of device that couldn’t be installed if there are any intruders in the necessary parts of the dungeon.

“… Well, since we separated the rooms on the floor with doors, when the time comes we’ll turn the core room into an impregnable trap room.”

By dividing the floors up, we can set up traps even if there’s an intruder on another floor.
… Naturally, that’s if there aren’t intruders in the room. That condition still counts.

“But right now the bandit boss is lying in wait in the core room.”

Of course, the bandits are treated as intruders.

“Yeah… in other words, right now we want them to overlook us and appeal to them as a harmless dungeon.”
“I get it, so that’s why I can’t take the corpses. Then, how will they overlook us?”
“… F-for now we just wait and see.”

In fact, there was nothing he could do for now.
He returned his attention to the group of knights.

[Is the loot room this way? A bed… u-]
[… That’s a distinctive smell. Were there women here as well? But, they didn’t use [Cleanup]… there’s so much that even if they used it it wouldn’t be enough.]

Right now, the knights were examining the boss’ bedroom.
It’s the room that he made the dog-eared girl his plaything. By the way, the dog-eared girl is under the bed right now. She had eyes like a dead fish and didn’t even twitch. Without finding her, the knights moved on to the next room.
Though the knights probably would have been able to find her if they used [Life Search], they didn’t use it for some reason. I wonder if there’s a usage restriction? The knights probably couldn’t use it just to simply explore. The captain-ish knight that had used [Life Search] outside of the dungeon was, right now, issuing instructions to subordinates at the entrance room.

The boss’ bedroom had been turned into a jail.
They did that in order to capture the guys that they attacked, but in the end they didn’t use it. It turned into a loot room.

[It’s not that good eh.]
[Was our timing off? If we’d come here a bit sooner there might have been some valuables. We replenished our rations… it looks like we came a bit too late…]
[Oi, watch what you’re saying. But well, isn’t it fine with this sake we got?]

Still, the knights retrieved the valuable items from this room before going to the master room. Though there really wasn’t anything worth mentioning. The bread was moldy and got thrown away… About the magic tool that could be used for light? It was like a lantern… Though well, the boss brought everything that could be used for combat to the core room.
So the only things left were old food and bad loot. Since it had become a dead end, the knights put the food into boxes and carried it out.

After they finished carrying the food out, they resumed the suppression.
Putting his hand to the wooden door, a knight tried to open it. A sword sprouted from the door.

[Guah!?]

It wasn’t a trap. Behind the wooden door was a bandit piercing the knight that tried to open the door.
Then, the door was completely destroyed with swords.

[Uoaaaaaah!]
[Gu-!? Ryan, get awa-! Uooooh!]

The injured soldier withdrew and combat began.

[Dammit, since they tried to ambush us at the entrance I was negligent… Light, heal this person’s wounds—[Healing]!]
[S-sorry, captain… gu-u…!]

Wrapped in the magic’s light, the injured soldier’s wounds were healed. The large slash wound closed and the bleeding stopped. Though he was still exhausted and weak, he wasn’t in a life-threatening situation.
… So that’s recovery magic huh. It’s my first time seeing it.
Ah, the combat finished while I was admiring it.

[Sorry, Haggis was also injured in the fight just now. Please heal him.]
[Damn, this is too exhausting… Can you take up command instead if I collapse? Light, heal this person’s wounds—[Healing].]
[There’s no other way so it can’t be helped. Since I can’t use recovery magic, just captain… Seriously, it’d be nice if more healing scrolls showed up on the market…]
[There definitely isn’t enough recovery magic scrolls produced, since the Church has a monopoly on it…]

Hmm, hearing that was good… By the way, it seems I can exchange 100000 DP for a healing scroll. Calling it rare… it’s the same price as the cheapest dragon. Yup.
However, if they’re able to recover from wounds they went to great lengths to inflict, there’s no longer a chance for the bandits to win.

[Alright then. I checked Ryan a little ago, be careful of surprise attacks okay? … Even though the [Ordinary Cave] is said to be a very short dungeon.]
[Captain. There are pickaxes on the ground. The bandits likely dug more.]
[Huh? The walls of a dungeon will be repaired even if they’re dug into. Why do they have something like that?]
[I don’t know, but… there are traces of them digging through walls.]

Is that so? I looked at Rokuko.

“Usually, the opened holes are closed up, yeah. Don’t humans do that too?”
“Like healing scratches huh.”
“Sort of like that. Though it isn’t particularly painful.”

[Hmm…? What does that mean? Though it was already a very unusual thing for bandits to set up in a dungeon, maybe this has something to do with that?”
[No way, the bandits are the dungeon boss?]
[Hahaha, I’ve never heard of something like humans being a dungeon boss. Maybe the bandits are dragons?]
[The rooms here are too small for dragons to fit in.]

The knights carefully advanced through the dungeon while joking around.
As for the remaining bandits, nine were lying in wait in the core room.
Though they had no choice but to take their time while looking through the eight rooms in the dungeon, the knights finally arrived in front of the core room… However, the knights didn’t know how to open the door to the core room.

I changed my view to the bandits.
An underling moved his ear from the door, reporting to the boss.

[… It looks like they arrived.]
[Alright. Prepare your bows, quietly… Shoot ’em dead soon as they open the door.]
[Boss, we got this.]
[Fuu. Those guys should be exhausted by getting here. If it comes to that, we’ll put an end to it and just push through.]

In reality they’ve recovered. I wonder what they’d do if I told them the knights had no chance of losing.
… I’d die from the core being destroyed in a fit of anger.

… Creeeak, the wooden door to the core room opened slowly.
The moment that happened, the bandit boss gave the signal to shoot their bows. Arrows shot towards the passage.
With heavy impact, there were the sounds of arrows hitting armor. However, just one of them. One of them was really lucky—and the worst case for the knights—that an arrow slipped into the visor’s opening, going through his brain.
At the corner of my vision I saw the DP increase. Looks like he died in one hit.

[Ryui! Dammit, it’s no good! He didn’t survive!]
[Tch…! Just one person!]
[Boss!]
[You guys! Go for their joints! Our armor will just deflect-]

The boss slashed at him.

[Geh-, you bastard, you Melon Vomit!]
[Don’t call me thaaaaaat!]
[Uwaaah!]

The bandit boss was enraged, slashing with his sword. His vigor engulfed the knight’s body, causing him to flinch. He rammed his sword into an opening on the knight’s armor—violently stirring up the insides. I saw the DP increase again, guess he died as well.
I don’t want to see what’s inside…
Rather, the heck kind of nickname is Melon Vomit?

[Wha-, impolitely vomiting melon while eating together with Hime-sama!]
[How dare you do that to Ryui and Eijin, you Vomit Bastard!]
[That melon was rotten! It wasn’t my fault! Why did you take my f*cking reward moneeeeeeeey!]
[More than just vomiting the melon, you killed the chef after falsely accusing him of making the melon rotten! Right in front of Hime-sama!]
[Shut up! He was just jealous that Hime-sama was in love with me! I would have been emperor right now if it wasn’t for him!]

Ah, thanks for explaining how you became Melon Vomit. I literally leaned more about it than I thought.
Thereafter, Melon Vomit struggled more than expected because he got so angry.
In addition to killing the guy with his sword, he inflicted many injuries on the knights.
But that was all.
With the cooperation of the subordinates supporting each other, they gradually wore him down. The knights successfully surrounded him, sealing off his movements.
Then, before he noticed it, a sword grew from his belly.

[Dammit… after that… even though…]

Dropping to his knees with a thud, Melon Vomit was defeated.
Grabbing his hair, the knight forcibly lifted his face.

[Oi, where are your other comrades? Melon Vomit.]
[Tch… everyone was here because of it, goddamn it… why… I did what I was told…]

Though his words near the end were faint, it reached the knight’s ears.
With that, all of the bandits had become DP.

[Was there a mastermind? … Though there was evidence there were women, maybe they escaped.]
[Though he said everyone… I don’t get it. Wait, it looks like this room is the dungeon core’s.]
[Heeeh, here… that’s a dungeon core huh? It’s the first time I’ve seen one.]
[As I’d heard, it was a small dungeon. There weren’t even stairs.]

One of the knights aimed his sword towards the dungeon core.

[Alright then, should I destroy the core?]

Ch12 - A Slave Called a Hug Pillow

The knight said he was going to destroy the core.
The statement was stifling.
Shivers ran through me as though my blood flowed in reverse.
The knight raised his sword in the monitor… then, swung it down.

“Gob!”
“Gobsuke!?”

Gobsuke rushed out into the master room. Rokuko and I couldn’t stop him.
That is, it may have been the instinct of a dungeon monster to avoid the core from being destroyed.

[Uwah-!? Kuh, that’s-!]
[Gob-… ah…]

In the monitor, we could see Gobsuke jump out of the core and be cut down.
Gobsuke was cut in two, breathing his last breath.

[Dammit, the goblin got in the way… let’s go again…]
[Oi, what are you doing!? This isn’t in our jurisdiction!]

The leader stopped the knight raising his sword over his head.

[Low class dungeons like this are controlled by the adventurer guild. Just a goblin came out, I heard that this is a bottom class dungeon.]
[Oops, that’s right… my apologies.]

Stopped by his captain, the knight quickly lowered his sword.

[… Shit, even though I could become a Sage Knight by destroying a dungeon core…]
[Though I get why you would want to destroy the core, it’s already been suppressed. Besides, if you could be acknowledged as a Sage Knight by subjugating bandits in a dungeon where there isn’t even a dungeon boss, the royal capital would be overflowing with them by now.]
[Tch… well, just one goblin came out of the core when I said I’d destroy it, maybe it didn’t get enough power…]
[Fool, I’m cutting your pay when we return.]
[Eeh-! That’s-!]

[Well, rather than gaining recognition as a Sage Knight with a dungeon where there isn’t even a dungeon boss, wouldn’t the opposite happen?]
[… If anything, couldn’t you call Melon Vomit the boss? When you receive your Sage Knight name, do you want it to said like [Travelling to the Ordinary Cave, the Sage Knight that suppressed Melon Vomit]? After that, you’d be known as [Sage Knight of Melon Vomit] or [Sage Knight of the Ordinary Cave].]
[Yeah, that sounds pretty bad… Haah, Ryui, Eijin, Thomas… I didn’t think three people would have been lost by something like a bandit extermination.]
[Melon Vomit was a formidable enemy…]

Leaving out their losses, the mood became one of work completed.
Remembering that I hadn’t been breathing for a while now, I took a deep breath.
… I thought I was going to die.
After coming to this world, that was the first time I’ve seen the sign of death.
Thought I was going to crap myself… seriously, ya know? Craaaaap myself.

However, he had his mind on what he heard them say about Sage Knights destroying dungeon cores.

“U-uu… G-Gobsuke…”

Rokuko was crouched down, sobbing.
Having said that, the goblin was a companion we’d spent time together with for the past half month.
As for memories… yeah, but they’re just memories of eating bread together.
I wonder what kind of relationship Rokuko had with him while I was sleeping?

“Leave after giving back my portion of the [Bean Paste Roll]…”

Apparently it looks like Rokuko did the same as me.

“Gobsuke… repaid his debt splendidly. If he didn’t stop them, we’d be dead.”
“Uu, my [Bean Paste Roll]…”

No, she was probably meaning to say [Don’t leave me and die… idiot…].
I selected an assortment of six sweetened buns, presenting them to Rokuko.

“Here, [Bean Paste Rolls] to cheer you up.”
“Eh-really!? I’m cheered up, cheered up! Super cheered up!”

Rokuko was so lively it was to the point that I seriously almost saw an aura around her.
Ah, now that I think about it, this girl was always a brute that sent goblins against adventurers.

“What’s this!? Though it’s black on the inside it’s somehow delicious! Ah, but this one is tasty too–”

… Incidentally, I still had to teach her about [Jam Buns]…

♦ ♦ ♦

The bandits’ corpses were gathered in the entrance room. It seemed that they would bring the knights’ corpses back home.
Though I honestly didn’t want to see their grotesqueness, I can’t look away so that I can catch the timing to turn them into delicious DP.
… Dousing the corpses with oil, they burned them… In the cave?
I get the feeling they don’t know anything about carbon dioxide stagnating in the air inside the dungeon in the first place. Even the bandits used torches for light as usual…

[Even a dungeon funeral is too luxurious for these guys.]
[Did you douse them with oil properly? It’d be troublesome if they became ghouls later on.]
[Yeah, it’s fine to just burn everything but their weapons yeah?]
[That’s right. In they off chance they somehow survive, it’ll be troublesome if they have anything.]

Though they said that, there wasn’t anything worth using left.
Just the bandits’ corpses and their bedding.
So that it would burn everything, they went outside the cave’s entrance before setting the fire. I was thankful for that, since after it burned out I could majestically capture the corpses.

[Alright, I’ll set the fire… Dance, flames—[Ignition].]

Ignition looked to be a magic that produced a fire to the level of a lighter from the fingertip. Igniting the oil fuse, the fire extended along it like a snake. The mountain of corpses inside the cave was wreathed in flames surprisingly quickly.

“Ah. Hey, is that dog eared slave girl alright?”

When I was reminded by Rokuko’s words, the fire snake burned through the wooden door, approaching the bed where the dog eared girl was hiding.
Her eyes like a dead fish reminded me of despair.
Maybe, even though the bandits were good, I get the feeling I won’t be able to sleep if I don’t save her here. Is it because she’s a child?
I’d be troubled if I had a nightmare… I’d lose out on sleep.

“… I wonder if she’ll become DP?”
“Cut it out. We’ll save her. Can’t you collect her?”
“Collect her huh? You’re going to go and help her now? The entrance room is a sea of fire you know? It’ll be burned out by the time you get there.”

It was like Rokuko said. Regardless of whether or not there were any intruders, you could only enter and exit from the dungeon core in the master room. And even if I left the dungeon core it was just a sea of fire. It was hopeless to just walk there.

“Besides, don’t you know that I can’t collect invaders? She isn’t an item.”

Hearing Rokuko’s words, it dawned on me.

“That’s it… an item. What did you just say, Rokuko?”
“Eh-?”

I spoke to Rokuko like I was persuading myself.

“Slaves are called tools. Items. In fact, I never saw those guys make any voluntary movements. Even after their owners, the bandits, died. In other words, slaves… are items, she just doesn’t have an owner now. Items of dead adventurers become the dungeon’s. Therefore, she already belongs to the dungeon. Right, Rokuko?”
“U-umm… even though they’re called items, they’re living things, having magical power…”
“Even if you called them living things, you can deploy demons directly from the dungeon core so long as there aren’t invaders. In other words, it’s possible to send and collect living things. In fact, couldn’t you collect the moldy bread? Isn’t mold a living thing? If that’s the case, you could probably collect a box with a mouse in it for example. So you should be able to collect living things like humans. It’s no good since there’s magical power? Even magic tools have magical power. Didn’t you collect the light magic tool? Therefore, there’s no reason you can’t collect THAT-!!”

I looked at the monitor and map. The fire spread to the bed, beginning to scorch the sheets.
The girl was shown as a red dot on the map, representing her as an intruder.
Shit, it’s still no good, I didn’t convince myself enough!

“A-a slave isn’t an item after all!”
“Then that isn’t even a slave! It’s a pillow! That is a pillow! A dog eared girl type of pillow! An item meant for men concealed under their beds!!”

That’s a pillow, a pillow, a pillow, a pillow, a pillow, a pillow, a pillow…
Imagine it. That is a hug pillow. A pillow that felt very good when you embraced it. Even playing with its dog ears would be amusing, and had the clothing option of adding knee-socks to it to caress and admire… ah, I should have been doing something like that.
Yeah, such an important hug pillow must not be burned.
Ah, I want to sleep using that pillow.
Maybe not having knee socks on its legs is also an option?
It would also be good to feel cold legs at times, rather than like a hot-water bottle. Speaking of hot-water bottles, the bandit boss used Rokuko’s core as a hot-water bottle huh? Ha ha ha.
Wait, I got a bit of topic.
Come to think of it, although there is an item called the heavenly pillow, I wonder if hug pillows are better than it?
… Ah, I remembered something unpleasant. Vomit Melon used it like that…
Though being used goods was a demerit, it won’t be a problem if I wash it thoroughly. Cleanup is really convenient. Can it wash hug pillows too?
Well then, if not I’ll just have to wash it thoroughly.

I could already only see the dog eared girl as a hug pillow.
Glancing at the map, rather than the red dot of an intruder, there was a green dot indicating an item.

“Alright, it’s a hug pillow. Collect it.”

In conclusion, she could do it.

♦ ♦ ♦

“Eeeeeh… H-how were you able to collect her!? She was an intruder, the master room—”
“Huh? I just collected a hug pillow. Rather, Rokuko, don’t absorb the corpses before the fire burns out. Wait a while after it finishes, a knight might come by to make sure.”

Ah, a bit of its hair got burned. Wasting such precious black hair. Well, it has an auto-restoration function so cutting a bit of it off should be fine. Maybe short is good too… Woah, there’s some white stuff stuck in it. Seriously Melon Vomit, clean up when you’re done.

“Eh-, i-is that right… No, no no. Wait a moment. If intruders can’t be brought into the core, it isn’t funny she was collected!”
“What are you talking about? Isn’t it natural that a hug pillow, therefore an item, could be brought in?”
“Y-yeah… I get the feeling that works…”

And so, I used Cleanup on the hug pillow.
As the foam characteristic to the Cleanup magic went from top to bottom on the hug pillow, it completely cleaned it off–

“Uoh-!?”

–and it let out a cute sound.
…Oh, I remembered. Right, I collected a dog eared slave girl.
Phew, I almost didn’t come back after my self-suggestion…

“G-good, I’m back. Right, somehow, I collected her…”
“Ah, you’re back? Then I demand an explanation!”
“Ah, that’s easy… It’s because I could.”

I thought I couldn’t do it so I convinced myself. Magic is a free and irresponsible thing… though now I’m tired.

“You saw it right? You can collect slaves.”
“That’s right… I can collect slaves…”

Yeah, it’s better to have Rokuko think that.
… Well, what do I do with this dog eared girl? For now, should I really make her a hug pillow…?

“By the way, what’s this one’s name? It’d be hard to refer to her without one.”
“Ah, that’s right… Your name? Or maybe your nickname? What is it?”
“Eh…. ah… … Meat… is what I’m called, Goshujin-sama.”

Though her reaction was a little dull, she answered properly.
For the time being, I laid down for the day, taking out sweet rolls and a futon and pillow combo with DP, having her rest.
Though she didn’t move at first, she obediently ate the sweet rolls when ordered and laid down, sleeping on the futon.
For information on how to treat Meat it might be good if the group of knights returned.
Above that, it’s better that the knights don’t meddle.

♦ ♦ ♦

In the end, the group of knights confirmed that the bandits’ corpses burned sufficiently before returning.
As expected, I slept through the whole thing.
After that, they returned to their camp without doing anything in particular. Yeah, I think it would have been amazing if they’d just slaughtered the bandits to eat their roasted meat. Truly.
Turning the corpses into DP wasn’t a problem, it also became a significant influx.
With this, our savings are totaled at—14504 DP.

“Amazing… this is the first time I’ve seen so much DP.”

Right now, when compared with our DP savings so far it was a small fortune.
However, the bandits aren’t here anymore, so our income decreased.
Gobsuke isn’t here anymore… but in exchange I have a dog eared slave and have to support it.
With three meals a day, assuming that sweet roll assortments and beverages are served… that’s a consumption of 15 DP per day.
And the income from the core was just 10 DP. It seemed that the dog eared slave earned 0 DP even when left alone since it was collected as an item. Or maybe it isn’t strong enough to collect DP from to start with…
Well, that being the case, I’ll cut her meals to two a day to make it stabilize… no, in order for adventurers to not expect anything when they come, I need to take out a goblin. There would be a deficit. Could I sleep soundly in a situation like this? No, I couldn’t sleep. I’m a coward, so I can’t endure my savings being gradually decreased.

So, I who cannot endure a deficit management style, will have to fundamentally change the [Ordinary Cave]’s nature.
… Haah, I don’t want to work.